

Web • C# • Developer

connelhooley.uk • me@connelhooley.uk • LinkedIn

Background

I am a 31-year-old software engineer based in Norwich. My preferred language is **C#** although I also have experience with modern web technologies such as **Node.js** and **React**.

I take an interest in **F#** and functional programming, I have written an in-depth article introducing C# developers to F# that you can find here. I also have experience with the Actor model via **Akka.NET**. I wrote an Akka.NET unit test framework that you can find here. I have written an article discussing the different ways a React application can be styled that you can find here.

My hobbies include playing football and table tennis. I am a Newcastle United fan.

Experience

Lead Developer Aviva

Jan 2022 - Present

I will begin a new role as a formally recognised Lead Developer upon returning from paternity leave in January, building on experience gained in my previous Aviva role.

Applications Developer Aviva

Apr 2018 - Dec 2021

During this role I have predominantly worked on an existing greenfield project, aimed at minimising duplication amongst various code bases within the business. The project used **Akka.NET** for its backend and **SignalR** to update a React SPA. My existing knowledge of Akka.NET has been very valuable to the team.

Upon my arrival in the team, I quickly provided value by improving the stability of the unit tests for the solution which often required re-runs to pass.

Whilst working on the project I became a tech lead. I have been a **lead developer** on multiple projects. This involved raising stories, assisting with backlog prioritisation, gathering requirements, liaising with the business, assisting other developers in team, gate-keeping pull requests, managing dev ops pipelines, doing production deployments and running scrum ceremonies when the scrum master was unavailable.

During my time at Aviva, I also wrote a simple service virtualisation tool that multiple teams used for over a year as an alternative to LISA/Dev Test before the business migrated to <u>WireMock</u>. This was written in **TypeScript** and **Node.JS**.



Web • C# • Developer

connelhooley.uk • me@connelhooley.uk • LinkedIn

Applications Developer Modality Systems

Feb 2015 - Mar 2018

During this role I worked on various solutions built around **Skype For Business**. I helped the dev team build out release pipelines in **VSTS** and embrace TDD & testing automation. This involved a large mentality shift with regards to how QA was approached. We tried to involve our testers as early as possible with each user story. I particularly enjoyed embracing TDD.

I led the design of one project that involved the co-ordinating of over 50 machines. It used **Akka.NET** and **SignalR** to achieve the distributed computing required. The machines could be configured using an **Angular2 TypeScript** web application. During this project we hired a junior dev whom I mentored which was an extremely rewarding experience. I was also stand-in scrum master for this project. I was involved in various Microsoft TAP programs during my time in this role which was very interesting.

Applications Developer C A Design Services

Jan 2014 – Jan 2015

This was my first development role. I initially performed small support tasks and developed inhouse .NET solutions. I then moved on to developing enhancements and bug fixes to existing products. These systems were usually 3-tier ASP.NET Web Form Applications with T-SQL databases. I eventually began working on new projects and was the first person at the company to make a website using an ORM back-end (Entity Framework) and the MVC design pattern (ASP.NET MVC). My first project was for the large retail firm Sainsbury's. I also began writing unit tests for the first time during my time at C A Design Services.

Qualifications	
BSc Hons in Software Engineering	University of East Anglia 2010 – 2013
2:2	
BTEC National Diploma in ICT	Great Yarmouth College 2008 – 2010
Triple distinction	
GCSEs	Cliff Park High School 2002 – 2006

Grade A: English Language Grade B: English Literature

Qualifications

Grade C: Science × 2, Maths, Statistics, ICT, Electronics, Art, PE, RE